NELSON LAU

732 Twin View Drive, Honolulu, HI 96817 | (808) 721-1233 | nelson.p.lau@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

As a highly motivated and versatile professional with 5 years of experience in Insurance, I am eager to transition my skills and experience to a career in web development. I am currently taking the Generation Coding Bootcamp and learning various skills such as Javascript, programing fundamentals, git, and coding specific problem solving. I am a quick learner, highly adaptable, and committed to delivering quality work. As a team player with excellent communication skills, I thrive in collaborative environments and am able to work effectively with people at all levels of an organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3Schools JavaScript Certification (in progress; expected date of completion 09/2023)

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS

- Bootstrap
- Unit Testing with Mocha
- Gi

EXPERIENCE

Generation Junior Web Developer Program

Feb 2023 to Sept 2023

Training Participant (in progress)

- Participating in an 11-week, 350+ hour Junior Web Developer program that emphasizes hands-on practical application
- Learning fundamentals of JavaScript, programming fundamentals, developer tools, git and problem solving

First Insurance Company of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, (Corporate Underwriting Department)

Filing Analyst I (Full-Time)

July 2019 to Present

- Research, interpret and communicate new and existing regulatory requirements to business partners in a timely and efficient manner
- Provide support in the analysis and preparation of rates, rules, and form filings to the Insurance Division; including development of proposals to management and coordinating all necessary filing work with actuaries, underwriters, and IT
- Assist with development and implementation of policy forms from beginning to end. Includes technical
 analysis of new coverage or coverage differences between a new and current form, obtaining input from
 Underwriting, Claims and Legal
- Develop underwriting knowledge and understanding of products & processes to support product development and process improvements within the underwriting departments
- Submits filings in the online filing system SERFF(System for Electronic Rates & Forms Filing) on behalf of my company to the State of Hawaii's Insurance Division

Filing Analyst Trainee (Full-Time)

May 2018 to July 2019

- Assisted with the analysis and review of policy forms
- Identified the differences between new and current forms for all applications
- Monitored updates released by Insurance organizations and maintain circular log, including communication of mandatory and/or statutory updates
- Assisted in the analysis and preparation of rates, rules and form filing to the Hawaii's Insurance Division

Associate (Corporate Underwriting) (Temporary)

February 2018 to April 2018

Graduated: December 2017

- Effectively revised endorsement forms according to the Standard Operating Procedure
- Moved files from the old database into Sharepoint to ensure that information is found in one place
- Accurately retyped forms that were not in Word Version in a timely manner

EDUCATION

University of Hawaii at Manoa, Honolulu, Hawaii
Bachelor of Arts in Economics with a Minor in Communicology